Deans' and Directors' Meetings; Records ua400.004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records
1967-1981
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Deans' And Directors' Meetings
ua400.004
1.0 cubic ft.
Records of informal meetings attended by deans of academic schools and directors of university facilities.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
These records were donated to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives, University Libraries by M.E. Grenander, by Kenneth D. Mosher, Jr., Class of 1946 in 1998. 1998
Biographical History
The Deans' and Directors' Meetings were informal meetings attended by deans of academic schools and directors of University facilities with the Academic Vice President presiding. The exact date at which these meetings began is unknown, but records in this collection begin in 1967. The purpose of these meetings was to provide and open forum for the discussion of matters of academic and administrative concern to the deans and directors of the University.
The record group also contains the records of the separate Conference of Deans of Faculties. The purpose of this group was to "serve as a continuing advisory body to the Vice-President of Academic Affairs." Specifically, it advised on "allocations of resources, future development of new and established program areas, and educational strategies for achieving University goals." (Memorandum from the Acting Vice-President for Academic Affairs to Charles Colman, et. al., 10/22/1970.) The Conference of Academic Deans met every other week following the Deans' and Directors' Meetings.
Scope and Contents
The records of Deans' and Directors' Meetings are an unofficial record of this group. This collection has been taken from the files of Dean Warren Haynes, School of Business, Associate Dean Charles Colman, School of Humanities, and circa James Schmidt, Director of University Libraries, as well as other deans and directors. Included in these files are minutes of meetings, memoranda, extensive documentation on the creation of budgets, allocations, admissions and enrollment figures, numerous reports on tenure and term appointment, and handwritten minutes by the aforementioned Deans and Directors. In addition, discussion can be found on major issues confronting the University such as student unrest in the late 1960's and the cancellation of many programs at the State University of New York at Albany due to state budget cuts in the mid-1970's.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series, arranged chronologically.
College administrators--New York (State); UAlbany Reference Collections; State University of New York at Albany.
- Agendas and minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 1)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes a statement of policy for the Conference of Deans of Faculties; Rules and Regulations for Maintenance of Public Order; and the Report of Ad Hoc Committee on Term Appointments., 1969 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 2)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes a memorandum on the establishment of Conference of Academic Deans., 1970 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 3)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes a summary report by Committee on Campus Unrest, a proposal for the establishment of the University Archives, and an Ecological Policy for SUNY, 1971 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 4)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes "Proposal of Resource Management.", 1972 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 5)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes "Statement on Professional Ethics.", 1973 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 6)
- Agendas and minutes - Contains "Report on Future Decline of College Aged Students.", 1973 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 7)
- Agendas and minutes - Contains Business School Accreditation by AACSB., 1974 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 8)
- Agendas and minutes - Contains "Procedures for Promotion and Continuing Appointments.", 1974 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 9)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes the "Preliminary Bylaws for SUNYA Council of Academic Deans.", 1975 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 10)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes "Confidential Report on Recommended Program Cuts.", 1976 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 11)
- Agendas and minutes - Contains "Grievance Procedure for Review of Allegations of Discrimination.", 1977 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 12)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes reports by Acting Director of Planning on national enrollment trends, enrollment trends at SUNYA,and enrollment trends for minorities and women., 1977 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 13)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes a report to Undergradute Academic Council "Goal of a Liberal Education.", 1978 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 14)
- Agendas and minutes, 1978 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 15)
- Agendas and minutes, 1979 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 16)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes staff report, "Regents Higher Education Planning.", 1979 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 17)
- Agendas and minutes - Includes report, "Measurement of Teaching Effectiveness.", 1980 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 18)
- Agendas and minutes, 1980 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 19)
- Agendas and minutes, 1981 (Box 1 (Deans' And Directors' Meetings Records), Folder 20)